today we're going to take a look at and
write some code with the highest paid
programming language that is according
to the stack overflow developer survey
of 2022 so before we get started looking
at the language that is going to make us
all rich let's first take a look at some
key findings on this year's survey
javascript is the most popular language
followed by html css sql and python and
node.js and react.js are the most
popular frameworks followed by the
online jquery most professional
developers use windows but very few use
wsl or windows subsystem for linux now i
don't know why since wsl makes
developing in windows an absolute
pleasure by the way if you want to set
up your windows with wsl like a pro then
please click the link below because
there you will find a free tutorial in
how to do so rust is still the most
loved programming language followed by
elixir rust python typescript and go are
the languages that developers want to
use the most if you also want to learn
python typescript or go click the link
below because you're going to find free
courses on them as well last year zvelt
was the most loved web framework and we
made a video highlighting what makes it
so lovable this year svelte is followed
by dino the project of the creator of
node.js dino has grown quite a lot with
a new framework called fresh endino
deploy but unlike last year zvelt is not
the most loved web framework anymore it
was overtaken by phoenix a web framework
for the elixir programming language we
can think of phoenix as ruby on rails or
python's jungle it is very powerful and
fast it can handle 2 million connections
per second in a single machine phoenix
is also the highest paid web framework
this year let me know in the comments if
you would like to see a video about dino
or phoenix and we will make it happen
the highest paid programming language
this year is closure ringing more than
one hundred thousand dollars it was also
last year's highest paid programming
language bringing in more than 95
thousand dollars this means that closure
developers got a pay bump this year
chucamida clogger is a functional
programming language that i think is
very elegant very beautiful and very
easy to read and understand clojure runs
on the jvm which is the java virtual
machine which allows it to call java
code it's used in production by many big
companies and it can also be compiled to
javascript using something called
clojurescript and it's also one of the
best programming languages to get
started with what is the drug of
functional programming that everybody
gets addicted to once they try it so now
i would like to give you a tiny
introduction to clojure by showing you
some code that i promise you are going
to understand if you are a developer of
any kind in clojure everything starts
with a list and here is how a list of
numbers will look like as you can see we
don't need to use commas and spaces are
enough in closure code is data which is
a hard concept to grasp but what it
basically means is that code is written
like a data structure looking for us
that data structure is the list which we
already saw the syntax to call a
function enclosure looks like this the
function name always goes at the start
of the list and everything else that
follows it are just arguments so for
example to print a line in the console
with the numbers 1 2 and 3 we will do
something like this
or to add them all up we can use the
plus function we can also find the
highest or lower number if we want to
easy peasy now that we know how to use
functions let's move on to create our
own function what i want to do now is to
make a function that returns the text
hello to create a function inside of a
list we will write def n and then the
name of the function in the square
brackets we write the parameters which
for now as you can see don't exist and
finally we just return hello as you can
see we don't need to write return in
closure it happens automatically to make
our function say hello with the name of
the user inside of the square brackets
we will write the name as a parameter
and then we will use the str function to
concatenate the strings to call this
function all we have to do is this but
what if somebody calls our hello
function without the name of the user
how do we handle that case instead of
using if else we can use something
called a multi-arity function which i
absolutely love for this we will write
two versions of our function one with
the parameters and one without them so
now if we call our hello function
without any arguments the first case of
the function will run
the first case will call the hello
function again but this time anonymous
will be an argument
then the second case of the hello
function will run which will return
hello anonymous it's so elegant and last
but not least we have something called
the thread last macro which is something
incredibly cool threadless allows us to
take a piece of data and put it through
functions to transform it here we have a
vector which is like an array this
vector is full of floating point numbers
or floats then we call the map function
with the int function as an argument to
convert each float in the vector to an
integer after that is done we call the
distinct function on the data to remove
any duplicated numbers then we call the
remove function with the even function
as an argument to remove all the even
numbers then we call the sort function
to organize the items from small to big
and finally we get the last item and
print it on the console look at the code
it doesn't even look like code it's
beautiful it's functional and it's
declarative it's great that was just a
tiny introduction to closure and i'm
very curious to know what you think
about it on the comments did you like
closure what do you think about it do
you want to learn more maybe are you a
closure developer what do you use
closure for let me know all of that in
the comments i'm going to be looking at
them right now thank you as always for
watching stay free stay healthy stay
happy eat dingy ham samidah salaam hey
yo see you on the next one bye